Sergey Gezin Data Analyst

Yandex Data Analyst program graduate with preceding experience working with huge amount of road traffic data as a project specialist. Skilled in Python, SQL, Tableau, Excel, VBA, VB.NET. Outside-the-box thinker, fast and eager learner, passionate and curious about data, technology, and science.

Skills

Software: Python, SQL, Tableau, A/B Testing, Excel, VBA, VB.NET, Machine Learning, Basic HTML & CSS. **Personal:** Multitasking, Excellent analytical skills, Self-learning abilities, Attention to details, Ability to solve problems, Good communication skills.

Languages: Russian – Native, Hebrew – Fluent, English – Fluent.

Work Experience

2016 - PRESENT

Project Specialist / Shiran Survey & Research, Jerusalem, Israel

- Experienced as Junior Data Analyst on Highway 4 Planning project data preprocessing and analysis.
- Was responsible for turning road traffic video records into clean data and building reports in 100+ projects.
- Provided coordination for 10+ manual data collectors.
- Expanded and updated existing report building software (VBA, SQL) and developed manual tools for traffic counting and automatization from scratch (VB.NET).

2014 - 2016

Field Coordinator / Taskir Survey & Research, Tel Aviv, Israel

- Organized, scheduled and instructed the field personnel to cover survey operations.
- Maintained field survey equipment.

2014 - 2014

Pollster / Datasense Ltd, Tel Aviv, Israel

• Active field polling and conducting surveys, collecting public opinion.

Education

2020-2021

Data Analyst / Yandex Practicum Israel - Online course

Extensive program included 12 Python-based projects, focused on EDA, Statistical DA, SQL, Business Analytics, Data-driven Business Decisions (A/B testing), Automation, Machine Learning, and Tableau, Cohort Analysis, Business Metrics (ROI, RPC, CRR).

2004-2008

Chemistry / Ural State University, Ekaterinburg, Russia

Achievements

City Math Olympics – 2nd place; Region Chemistry Olympics – 3rd place.

Interests

Space and Aviation, Arduino, History.